# Tom Christian, UI Designer / Developer

As an experienced user-interface designer & front-end developer with 6+ years of commercial experience, I specialise in designing & developing single page webapps & responsive websites. I'm a keen follower of Agile & iterative design backed by A/B & multi-variant split testing.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Front-end Developer, Tribal Worldwide Nov 2016-Jan 2017

 Building Unilever product websites upon a SASS, Backbone.js & Handlebars powered framework

# Front-end Developer, Audio Network Jul 2015-Nov 2016

- Converted the front-end of Audio Network's existing website into a responsive solution powered by Bootstrap and SASS
- Built the front-end of a SPA music library plugin for Adobe
  Premiere Pro using Angular 2 (written in typescript) and SASS
- Setup front-end tooling with gulp.js to support building of SASS components, JS modules and icon fonts
- Designed a cross-platform (OSX/Windows) Electron based installer for fast delivery of the Adobe plugin
- Wrote unit tests in Jasmine using the Karma test runner & e2e acceptance tests with protractor
- Delivered incrementally in two-week sprints with key decisions arising from extensive A/B and multi-variant testing

# Front-end Developer, Concise Media Design 2012–July 2015

- Designed and developed the UI of Concise's flagship event product with OOJS and SASS
- Developed a bespoke medical simulator app for a leading diabetes pharmaceutical client used at a conference by 900 attendees.
   Built with JS, PHP and SQLite
- Developed an analytical reporting tool to output statistics of app usage during live events. Built with jQuery and Flot.js
- Worked alongside back-end developers to create robust & reusable async JS to heavily integrate with REST based API's.
- Worked with key clients such as Adidas, Accenture, Bank of America, BT, Shell, Goldman Sachs, Morgan Stanley, JP Morgan, UBS, HSBC, Novo Nordisk and VISA

## Front-end Developer, Web Infinity Jul 2011–Sep 2011

- Developing jQuery powered user interfaces for Web Infinity
- Working directly with clients such as NetApp, Iomega and UK Gigs Online

# Front-end Developer, Invision Power Services 2009-2011

- Hired after becoming the most trusted and profitable 3rd-party theme developer within the forum community
- Tailored Invision's community forum platform to integrate with the brand & UI of major clients including NFL, NHL, NBC, Warner Bros, Skype, Roxio, Intuit and Baltimore Ravens

#### SKILLS / TOOLS

HTML, CSS, SASS, BEM

JS, ES6, jQuery

Angular(2), Typescript

ISON, XML, REST API's

NodeJS, PHP, MySQL

Bower, NPM, Gulp

PhoneGap, Ionic

Bootstrap, RWD

Agile, Scrum

Version Control (GIT)

W3C Standards, ARIA

## **EDUCATION**

## **UWE**, Bristol

2009-2012

B.Sc(h) Web Design.

## **Brockenhurst College**

2007-2009

Five AS/A-Levels.

## CONTACT

hello@elseif.io

(+44) 755 3121 812

http://tomchristian.co.uk

http://github.com/tctc91

@tomchristian91